Nathaniel Williams

Birmingham, Alabama, United States



nmwilliams87@gmail.com



205.213.7922



linkedin.com/in/nathaniel-williams-64a7b13b

Summary

I care deeply about building Quality Culture within Technology teams and have a passion to propel my team forward to success.

I am a skilled, professional, and experienced software tester with a vast knowledge of DevOps, Agile development, and Test Automation. I am well versed in multiple software testing approaches and have a strong commitment to accuracy, efficiency, and teamwork.

Experience



RxBenefits, Inc.

Aug 2021 - Present (11 months +)

- Drive QA best practices across multiple Agile/SCRUM teams
- · Foster cross-team and cross-department collaboration
- Drive continuous improvement using tools and QA metrics to meet quality goals
- · Support QA efforts for projects as an individual contributor
- Take action as a problem solver when issues or roadblocks to the team's success are present
- Communicate and escalate information about timetables and milestones that may not be met
- Mentor QA Engineers
- Advocate for high standards on test and code quality
- Establish and monitor progress toward quarterly goals for each team member
- Conduct quarterly and annual performance reviews
- Actively participate in departmental and project team meetings
- · Design automated test specs in Cypress
- Mentor QA Engineers in automated spec creation

Software Quality Engineer

RxBenefits, Inc.

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021 (3 months)

- · Develop and maintain test plans, test scripts, and test results
- Perform manual System, Functional, API and Integration testing as well as Performance testing where appropriate
- · Contribute to the project planning process by estimating QA tasks and deliverables
- Effectively document software defects and proactively communicate defect details and impact to the team
- Participate in departmental and project team meetings
- · Communicate and escalate information about timetables and milestones that may not be met
- Collaborate with the development, test automation, product support, and product management teams in an agile environment
- Recommend QA and/or team process optimization improvements

- · Mentor and share knowledge with team members
- Support your team through encouragement and by example

Software Test Engineer

Daxko

Mar 2016 - Jun 2021 (5 years 4 months)

- Worked closely with my Development Team to produce creative and innovative solutions to complex testing problems
- Proactively mitigated risks for planned epics and projects by understanding the "why?" behind our features
- Designed and created automated test specs in Ruby, using Selenium, Page-Object, Watir, etc.
- Designed SQL queries to test Data Integrity, Referential Integrity, and general Database Accuracy
- Performed Database testing, Web testing, and REST API testing
- Presented new system features and defect fixes to stake holders in bi-weekly sprint reviews
- Served as team Scrum Master to promote efficiency, teamwork, and continuous improvement
- Organized and facilitated project planning, daily stand-up meetings, sprint reviews/demos, retrospectives, release planning, and other Scrum-related meetings
- Acted as Release Train Conductor by managing code branches, coordinating regression efforts, and performing production releases on a bi-weekly cycle

Senior Customer Success Specialist

Daxko

Mar 2015 - Mar 2016 (1 year 1 month)

- Worked directly with Customer Success Team Members to train, teach, and consult end-users on how best to utilize our software products
- Mastered each phase of our SAAS product package, including mobile, accounting, reporting, fundraising, membership, programs, and child care modules
- Actively taught Customer Success Team Members through 1:1 paired case work and hands-on techniques. I empowered team members in asking the correct questions of customers to get needed answers in order to solve issues swiftly and effectively
- Led the Custom Reports writing team and managed all report requests
- Acted as Sales Team Liaison, assisting in sales demos, fulfilling unique customer report requests, and answering all system functionality questions for Sales team members

Customer Success Team Member

Daxko

Mar 2013 - Mar 2015 (2 years 1 month)

Senior Team Leader

Target

Sep 2011 - Apr 2013 (1 year 8 months)

- Directly managed seven in-store departments; Designed and maintained sales planners; Increased designated sales area by 12.7% compared to the year previous
- Interviewed, trained, and performance managed employees; Developed training routines and storewide service themes to increase guest survey scores

- Trained Executive Team Lead interns in day-to-day store operations, department specific tasks, and employee management
- Performed Leader on Duty shifts weekly; Led employees and performed opening/close-out duties; Store T2503 saw 10.6% sales increase vs. the year previous (#1 in District 340)

Shift Manager

Delectable Brands

Jun 2010 - Sep 2011 (1 year 4 months)

- · Designed work schedules for employees
- Created store purchase orders based on inventory; Worked with vendors regarding the presentation and distribution of the product
- Managed yogurt machines and inventory; served customers
- Led employees and performed close-out/opening duties using point of sale system.
- Maintained clean and attractive store; managed money with integrity
- Developed advertising and marketing ideas; worked with the University of Alabama Marketing Department

Education



Bachelor of Science (BS), Marketing 2007 - 2011